Olin Kirkland

Brühler Landstraße 2, 50997 Köln, Germany plakat@live.com; +49 162 372 0898 https://www.olinkirk.land

SUMMARY

I am an adaptable programmer and front-end developer with a passion for making games, producing high quality OOP code, and designing user interfaces. My professional experience includes core front-end development for large scale applications, game development, and exhibit design. In my free time, I work on personal game-related projects with an emphasis on procedural generation.

SKILLS

- * Programming languages: Actionscript 3 (+Apache Flex), Haxe (+OpenFl), C# (+PlayerIO), Javascript
- * IDEs: IntelliJ IDEA, Microsoft Visual Studio, FlashDevelop, Flash Builder
- * Design: Adobe Animate, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop
- * Communication: Native speaker of English and German

EDUCATION

George Mason University, Fairfax, VA, United States

Completed coursework towards a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science September 2011 – June 2013

Oakton High School, Fairfax, VA, United States

Graduated with Advanced Placement September 2007 – June 2011

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

References to Adobe Air/Adobe Flash imply the language Actionscript 3

BRIGHT FUTURE, Cologne, NRW, Germany

Game Developer, April 2020 – Present

- * Work closely with other programmers and designers to develop and maintain a massively-multiplayer browser game
- * Develop tools for other departments
- * Debug and refactor the game's codebase with an emphasis on improving performance
- * Work collaboratively using version control (Perforce and Git)
- * Technologies: Haxe, OpenFl, Trello, Jira

DALLMEIER, Regensburg, BY, Germany

Flex Developer, May 2018 - April 2020

- * Worked closely with other programmers and designers to develop user interfaces
- * Developed various interactive modules for displaying and visualizing data
- * Worked collaboratively using version control (Git)
- * Technologies: Adobe Air, Apache Flex, Redmine

HOUSTON MUSEUM OF NATURAL SCIENCE, Houston, TX, United States

Freelance Front-end Developer (Freelance), September 2017 – May 2018

- * Developed interactive touch screen applications and kiosks for deployment in the Houston Museum of Natural Science
- * Worked closely with curators to build content-rich exhibits to inform and entertain visitors
- * Organized and led meetings with museum docents and volunteers
- * Designed and developed a cutting edge interactive kiosk using LEAP Motion technology
- * Technologies: Adobe Air, Adobe Flash, Apache Flex, C#, LEAP Motion

PAUL BERNHARD EXHIBIT DESIGN AND CONSULTING, Houston, TX, United States

Front-end Developer, September 2015 – May 2018

- Developed interactive touch screen applications and kiosks for deployment in the Houston Museum of Natural Science
- * Directed the organization and implementation of museum content for custom applications
- * Wrote code to interface with custom hardware (sensors like the LEAP Motion and Arduinos)
- * Produced maps based on custom data sets using industry standard GIS tools
- * Programmed visualizations for data from a wide variety of formats and sources including data from RESTful APIs related to the energy sector and extensive industry data sets
- * Communicated with engineers, graphic designers, and researchers during development
- * Created concepts and layouts as detailed storyboards for graphic designers to build on
- * Managed and carried out the deployment of applications to their intended hardware
- * Technologies: Adobe Air, Adobe Flex, Flash, C#, PlayerIO, Unity, HTML, Javascript, Arduino

RENAISSANCE CHILD, Arlington, VA, United States

Camp Instructor (Full time), April 2015 – September 2015

- * Created lesson plans and activities relating to subjects including mechanical engineering, stop-motion, programming, and robotics
- * Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting

FREELANCER

Interactive Media Developer and Graphic Designer, June 2013 – April 2015

- * Conferred with clients to discuss and determine layout design, and functionality of software
- * Developed and implemented graphics and layouts for company applications
- * Reviewed final layouts and suggested improvements as needed
- * Maintained an organized archive of versions and products

GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY, Fairfax, VA, United States

Flash Developer, January 2012 – May 2013

- * Developed a series of interactive web applications to allow users to explore university floor plans, place furniture in dorms, and virtual tours
- * Technologies: Adobe Flash